EMMANUEL TUGBEH, MNCS

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CONTACT INFO

Email: etugbeh@outlook.com
Telephone: (+234) 8169960927
Location: Ajah Lagos 101245, NG

SOCIAL LINKS

LinkedIn:linkedin.com/in/2gbehGitHub:github.com/2gbehFigma:figma.com/@2gbeh

Kaggle: kaggle.com/emmanueltugbeh

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Master's degree (M.Sc.) in Computer Science
 Advanced Software Engineering

University of Benin, Edo, NG. Apr 2019 - Feb 2021

 Bachelor's degree (B.Sc.) in Mathematics & Computer Science

Benson Idahosa University, Edo, NG. Sep 2010 – Jun 2014

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATES

- (2021) GoodTalentLabs UI/UX Design Mentor
- (2020) TBLF Virtual Teachers Program
- (2016) PushCV IT/Engineering Specialist
- (2015) HSE 1-3, First Aid & Fire Fighting
- (2014) Google Maps Engine Expert
- (2013) VConnect Hackathon Challenge

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend

HTML5, CSS3, AJAX, JSON, JQuery, Bootstrap, TailwindCSS, React.js (Next.js), React Hooks, Redux Toolkit, Next Auth, React Native (Expo), React Query, Vue.js (Nuxt), RxJS, AngularJS, Angular2, Java (JSP), Java Spring (MVC), GraphQL (Apollo Client), Material UI (MUI 3), Vuetify, Radix UI, Mantine UI/Hooks, Framer Motion, Formik, Yup, React Hook Form, Zod

Backend

Node.js (Express.js), TypeScript (NestJS), PHP (Laravel), Python (Django), Java (Servlets), Go, Golang (Gin), GraphQL (Apollo Server), React Email, Resend, Sequelize, Prisma, TypeORM, Socket.io, Interswitch SDK, Paystack (Stripe), Flutterwave SDK

Testing

Jest, Cypress, Pest, PHPUnit, JUnit, React Testing Library (RTL)

Database

MySQL, PostgreSQL (Supabase), MongoDB, RxDB, Redis Cache, Firebase

DevOps

Git, GitHub Actions, CircleCl, Jenkins, Vercel, NGINX, Linux, AWS (Amazon S3), Docker

Others

Android Studio, NetBeans, Microsoft Power BI, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Access (VBA), Kaggle, Adobe Dreamweaver, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe XD, CorelDraw Graphics Suite, Figma, Google Maps, Google Analytics (GA4), Google Sheets, Google Drive, Google Forms, Peachtree (Sage 50), SPSS

SOFT SKILLS

- Resourceful
- Detail Oriented
- Team Player & Mentor

CAREER SUMMARY

I'm a self-taught full-stack developer with over 10 years' experience in enterprise software development and IT training. I am a certified Web/Mobile App Developer, Data Analyst and Developer Community Mentor. My ideal tech stack includes; React.js (Next.js), React Native (Expo), Node.js + TypeScript (NestJS), PHP (Laravel), PostgreSQL (Supabase) and AWS (Amazon S3).

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Full-Stack Engineer Jan 2023 – Mar 2024

Spottr.app, Lagos, NG.

Location-based e-Commerce Platform:

- Created responsive and reusable UI components with Angular2 (15.x).
- Developed and integrated type-safe RESTful APIs using Node.js (NestJS) and PostgreSQL database.

Senior Frontend Developer (Remote)

Feb 2020 - Dec 2022

Buzzbite.io, London, UK.

Brand Campaign & Influencer Marketplace:

- Created responsive and reusable UI components with React (Next.js).
- Integrated RESTful APIs built with Laravel and MySQL database.
- Integrated payments using Paystack SDK.

Senior Backend Developer (Hybrid)

May 2017 - Dec 2019

Pear SDC, Delta, NG.

Benson Idahosa University's Admission Portal:

- Created RESTful APIs with Laravel and MySQL database.
- Integrated client-side business logic with Vue.js (Nuxt).
- Integrated payments using Interswitch SDK.

Mobile App Developer

Sep 2015 - Apr 2017

Appzone Group (Zone), Lagos, NG.

Core Banking Solutions:

- Designed internet and mobile banking app screens for Providus Bank MFB using React Native (Expo 15).
- Built and deployed a customer self-service desktop application at Union Bank, Silverbird Galleria, VI.
- Integrated SAS Anti-Money Laundry (AML) solution at Sterling Bank HQ, Marina/CMS.

Data Analyst Feb 2013 - Aug 2015

NIIT Benin Centre, Edo, NG.

Technical Skills & Corporate Management Training:

- Developed student attendance and course completion tracking tool with Python and Django REST Framework.
- Taught Data Analytics using R, Microsoft Power BI and PostrgeSQL database.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Kotlin Developer Community

Mar 2019 – Dec 2021

- Organized weekly developer meet-ups centered on JetBrains products and services.
- Made use of Kotlin, IntelliJ IDEA, Android Studio, Figma, Google Sheets and Google Forms.

Google Student Ambassador (GDG)

Jul 2013 - Aug 2014

- Organized weekly developer meet-ups centered on Google products and services.
- Made use of AngularJS, Node.js, Adobe Dreamweaver, Google Maps, Google Drive and Google Forms.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Eventra - Event Attendance Tracker (PWA)

eventra.vercel.app

Built and deployed using Vue.js (3.x), Pinia, TypeScript, Firebase and Vercel.

ZEntry - Church Database Application (PWA)

zentry.vercel.app

Built and deployed using React.js (18.x), Redux Tookit, TypeScript, Firebase and Vercel.

Odara TV - Tech News, Movies & TV Shows

2gbeh.github.io/odara-tv

Built and deployed using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, AJAX, JSON and GitHub Pages.

SavingsBox MPCS (Fedora) – Personal Savings App

github.com/2gbeh/fedora

Designed and developed using React Native (Expo 49), TypeScript, Supabase and Vercel.

Aladdin RTK – Book Sales & Distribution Management Software

github.com/2gbeh/rtk

Built and deployed using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL and Apache/XAMPP Server.